

# **BENJAMÍN ESCOBAR**

FRONT-END DEVELOPER



Experienced mid-senior Front-end Developer with a strong background in HTML5, CSS3 (and SCSS preprocessor): Advanced understanding of JavaScript/Typescript and React.js with Hooks as well as Next.js framework for serverside rendering. Experienced in development of transactional, medical, e-commerce and geographic user-centric applications; employing GIT source control system under GitFlow workflow and RESTful API's.

I'm an active self-taught learner, teamwork oriented with Agile methodologies on interdisciplinary teams. Additionally, I have a keen interest in the hardware world and am a passionate musician.

#### **SKILLS**



HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, CSS Grid, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Angular Material, Material-UI

# JS Programming Technolgies:

Javascript/Typescript, React.js 16+, Next.js, Redux, Angular 2+ NgRx



Spanish: Native English: C1 Advanced



Email: <u>benjamin.sl.e@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: <u>@benjaseg</u>
YouTube: <u>bit.ly/DPyT\_YT</u>



## **JOB EXPERIENCES**

### Front-End Developer (React / Next)

#### Applaudo | Apr 2021 - Currently

- Develop and maintain high-performant front-end solutions using React and Next.js framework, adhering to best practices and DRY principles
- Build reusable pixel-perfect components, converting Figma designs into functional HTML/CSS pages with Tailwind CSS powered responsive interfaces to enhance the user experience.
- Write components documentation with Storybook
- Implement automated tests with Jest and perform code reviews to ensure code quality
- Apply agile methodologies, reporting progress and blockers in a timely manner, in a collaborative environment with multidisciplinary teams.
- Boost productivity with AI tools (Copilot, ChatGPT)

### Front-End Developer (React / Next)

AsteratNet | Jul 2020 - Dec 2020

- Implemented Backend for Frontend to handle RESTful API requests and JWT authentication
- Developed authentication flow, draggable task management, and data capture views

#### Front-End Developer (Angular)

Oralsys | Apr 2018 - Apr 2020

- Achieved rendering of 2D/3D X-ray images
- Developed user-friendly views for calendar, image gallery, and document templates creation modules
- Take leadership role with freelance developers

#### **Front-End Developer (Angular)**

CSUDO | Sep 2017 - Mar 2018

- Developed an interactive web map using Leaflet.js to visualize and analyze geospatial GeoJSON data
- Spearheaded front-end requirements for successful project kick-off



#### **FURTHER EXPERIENCES**

# Volunteer Full-Stack Developer (React / Strapi) Caritas | Jan 2021 - Jan 2023

- Streamlined medication supplies delivery process
- Handled user authentication and role-based security
- Implemented production-ready system on DigitalOcean server with docker implementation

#### **Full-Stack Engineer (MEAN)**

UPTOS | Oct 2016 - Sep 2017

- Leveraged Leaflet.js to overcome challenges in visualizing large geodatasets
- Designed UML artifacts for system lyfecycle
- Analyzed KPIs and developed components for insights



#### **EDUCATION**

# **Polytechnic University: UPTOS**

Engineering (Computer Science) | 2016 - 2022 Associate (Computer Science) | 2013 - 2016